Read family papers LCP.Read
Library Company of Philadelphia
- Series IV. John Read I
  - Correspondence: Family members including George Read, Thomas Meredith, Emily M. Hyde, Thomas Read, Thomas Meredith, 1785-1852 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Regarding land tract documents, legal information, 1794-1797 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence to Samuel Meredith, Treasurer of the United States, circa 1801 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence and documents regarding home on Baskin Island, Dauphin County, Pennsylvania, 1802-1806 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1802-1808, 1844-1845 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence with George Read, 1803-1804 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: T. Watkins to George Simpson, 1804 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence from Simpsons and Watkins relatives requesting financial assistance, promissory notes, 1804-1835 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1805-1860 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1808-1819 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence from George Read and various legal clients, 1809-1810 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Mostly regarding Samuel Barr and William Duncan, 1811-1812 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence to John Read Jr. concerning business matters, 1815-1829 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1817, 1820, 1823 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence with family members including John Meredith Read to father John Read Jr., 1817-1854 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence from Levi Hollingsworth, 1818, 1825 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Legal, financial, and family issues with related papers, circa 1826 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence with John M. Read and William Dickinson mostly regarding investments and stock, 1839-1843 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence concerning Lycoming lands, 1841 March 10-1842 January 26 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence concerning legal matters, W. B. Clymer, Susquehanna County land title disputes, 1843-1845 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with John M. Read and C.W. Caldwell regarding stock and investments, 1848 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence with John M. Read and C.W. Caldwell regarding stock and investments, 1849 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence from C. W. Caldwell and others to John Meredith Jr., 1850 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, business book, 1850-1853 (Volume 84)
  - Correspondence about business and the Episcopal Fund, 1851-1853 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence from C.W. Caldwell, Michael Meyfert, and others concerning financial and legal issues, 1851-1853 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Court Cases: Land dispute, 1813-1815 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Court Cases: Nicholson J. Wallis regarding Luzerne County, Pennsylvania, land dispute, 1816-1829 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Court Cases: Trustee for Kennedy, George W., 1820-1827 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Court Cases: Philadelphia Bank, 1820-1842 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Court Cases: Gilbert Smith Walker and Samuel Davis, 1823-1834 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Court Cases: Read versus Ross, 1826-1829 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Court Cases: Williams versus Watkinson, 1829-1833 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Court Cases: Solomon Allen and Moses Allen versus James M. Gould, 1830-1833 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Court Cases: Nathan Bunker versus city of Philadelphia concerning damages incurred from widening of Locust Street between Washington Street and 8th Street, 1833 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Court Cases: Railroad cases, 1836-1839 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Court Cases: Cochran versus Woodward, 1839 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Court Cases: Edward B. Grubb versus Henry Bayard, court notes involving mining in Lancaster County, Pennsylvania, 1850 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Estate of Samuel Meredith, 1772-1796, 1816 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Estate Benjamin Gibbs, 1784-1820 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Estate of George Read, 1786-1790 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Estate of George Read, promissory notes, 1789-1815 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Estate of Samuel Meredith, check stubs, 1790-1792, 1814 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Estate of John Morris regarding law library, circa 1798 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Estate of William Read with accounts with John Read Jr., 1798-1805 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Estate of Dr. Nathan Dorsey, 1798-1812 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Estates of William Read, George Read, James Read, 1800-1806 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Estates of Samuel Meredith, memoranda of monies received on account of Samuel Meredith, 1802, 1807 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Estate of Benjamin Gibbs, related correspondence, promissory notes, 1802-1819 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Estate of George Clymer, 1802-1822 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Estate of Elizabeth Meredith, 1807-1821 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Estate of Samuel Meredith, 1807-1828, 1853 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Estate of Thomas Bryan, 1807-1836 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Estate of John Read and Martha Meredith, George Read, Pennsylvania land purchase agreements, 1807-1839 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Estate of John Read of Newcastle County, Delaware with papers from and about William Read, George Read, and James Read, 1808-1813 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Estate of Esther Waters, account books, 1809-1832 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Estate of John Read and Martha Meredith, promissory notes, account vouchers, 1810-1823 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Estate of Rebecca Dickinson, account with Samuel Dickinson, executor of Rebecca Dickinson's estate, 1811-1827 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Estate of Samuel Meredith, legal papers, 1813 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Estate of Esther Waters, 1817, 1833-1835 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Estate of Samuel Meredith, John Read's account with the trustees of Samuel Meredith, 1817-1833 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Estate of Benjamin Gibbs, 1818-1820 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Estate of Samuel Meredith regarding Robert Gilmore and Sons, 1818-1820 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Estate of Samuel Meredith, receipts and payments, 1819-1824 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Estate of Samuel Meredith in account with John Read, 1819-1825 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Estate of Benjamin Gibbs, related materials and correspondence, 1819-1831 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Estate of George W. Kennedy, John Read Trustee for George W. Kennedy with Philadelphia Bank, 1820 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Estate of Rebecca Dickinson, 1820-1823 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Estate of Mary R. Eckard, 1823-1824 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Estate of Elizabeth Garrett, 1825 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Estate of Samuel Meredith, 1826-1830 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Estate of Esther Waters, 1833-1835 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Estate of Esther Waters, 1834 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Estate of Samuel Meredith, 1834-1841 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Estate of Peter Ozeas regarding Margaret Lucretia Nathans, 1835 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Estate of Samuel Meredith, maps and land tracts in Abingdon, undated (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Estate of Samuel Meredith, land tract information, undated (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Land tracts and deeds, legal correspondence, 1773-1797 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Land tracts and deeds, Luzerne County, Pennsylvania, 1784-1792 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Land tracts and deeds, Luzerne County, Pennsylvania, financial accounts list, 1784-1795 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Land tracts and deeds, Luzerne County, Pennsylvania, 1793 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Land tracts and deeds, Luzerne County, Pennsylvania, promissory notes, 1799-1804 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Land tracts and deeds, Luzerne County, Pennsylvania, 1804-1824 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Land tracts and deeds, Luzerne County, Pennsylvania, 1809-1815 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Land tracts and deeds, deed for William Duane and wife to Franklin Bache and others, 1820 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Land tracts and deeds, Luzerne County, Pennsylvania, 1820-1825 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Land tracts and deeds, Northern Liberties properties, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1830-1837 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Land tracts and deeds, surveys, bills, and receipts, circa 1849 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Subject File: Personal papers, General John Meredith Read, songbook, poems, wills, 1786-1854 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Subject File: Princeton papers, philosophy, 1785 December (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Subject File: Princeton papers, philosophy and other subjects, circa 1787 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Subject File: Princeton papers, an abstract of Powell's Treatise on Devises, with an abridgement of the law, regulating the estates of interstates in Pennsylvania, circa 1787 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Subject File: Research notes on a variety of academic subjects, circa 1787 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Subject File: Princeton papers, "Division of Simple Division" notebook, 1788 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Subject file: "Lands Claimed by Pennsylvania Owners", undated (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Subject File: List of claims presented to the Board of Common [Pleas] under the Sixth Article of the Treaty Amity [Plea] with Great Britain, 1798 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Subject File: William Read's China Voyage, 1804-1806 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Subject File: United Churches of Christ, account book by John Read, Church Warden, 1820-1826 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Subject File: United Churches of Christ, account information, correspondence, newsletters, 1820-1853 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Subject File: Commonplace book, 1822 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Subject File: United Church of Christ account book by John Read, Treasurer, 1825-1827 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Subject File: Marriage certificate of Judge John M. Read, 1828 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Subject File: Grand Lodge of Pennsylvania, Freemasons, 1832-1833 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Subject File: Grand Lodge of Pennsylvania, Freemasons, 1833-1835 (Box 31, Folder 9)
- Series V. Judge John M. Read II
  - [Judge John M. Read Jr.'s?] personal commonplace book with newspaper clippings, 1769-1854 (Volume 85)
  - Business papers, legal notes, and documents (mostly George Clymer, Samuel Meredith, and Isaiah Jones), 1790s-1820s (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Business papers and correspondence, 1791-1866 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Business papers and correspondence, 1792-1869 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - [Diary of S. Gretlet [?] (transcription)], 1796-1797 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1800-1809 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1810s (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Business papers and legal documents, 1816-1857 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Papers associated with Judge John Meredith's death, 1818-1880 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1820-1829 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Papers associated with Judge John Meredith's death, 1820-1975 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Papers associated with Judge John Meredith's death, 1820-1975 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Papers associated with Judge John Meredith's death, 1820-1975 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Papers associated with Judge John Meredith's death, 1820-1975 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Business papers, correspondence, newspaper clippings, 1820s (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence with Henry Clymer, George Clymer, and others, 1822-1825 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Business papers, receipt book, 1824-1837 (Volume 86)
  - Correspondence with William Davis and George Will, 1824-1825 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence from George Will and others, 1826 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, check stubs, and promissory notes, 1827 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Business papers, George McClellan vs. Francis Beattie, 1827-1829 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Read book, volume II: Old family letters collected by John Meredith Read, 1827-1851 (Volume 87)
  - Correspondence, promissory notes, check stubs, 1828 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence from Francis Engel and others, 1828-1829 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Business papers, legal notes (Windmill Island and Phoenix Iron Works), 1830s (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence and legal notes, 1830 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1830-1835 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1830-1839 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence and legal notes, 1831 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Business papers, legal notes concerning court cases relating to George Read, property damages filed against Philadelphia, and others, 1832 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Business papers, letter of attorney from Lazar Agabeg to Richard Willing and S. J. Sarkies, 1832 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Land information compiled by John Meredith Read and "A Short History of the Pumpelly or Pompilly," written by John Meredith Read Jr., 1832, undated (Volume 88)
  - Grand Lodge of Pennsylvania, Freemasons, correspondence, undated, 1832, 1833 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Read book, volume II: Old family letters collected by John Meredith Read, 1833-1881 (Volume 89)
  - Business papers, legal papers, estate of William McCall, Haines vs. Thomson, 1833 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Business papers, bill and receipts, 1834 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Business papers, correspondence, financial papers, 1834 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Resolution that a Bank of the United States is Unconstitutional, 1834 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Business papers, correspondence, memoranda, 1835 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence from Henry Muhlenberg, Van Buren, and Levi Woodbury, 1835-1837 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Business papers, correspondence, legal notes, 1835-1839 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Business papers, correspondence, and financial papers, 1836 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Business papers, correspondence, 1836 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Writings by young Emily Read and related correspondence from Priscilla Read and others, 1836-1841 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence and business papers, 1836-1886 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Appointment to Attorney for Eastern District of Pennsylvania, 1837 (Box 81, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence from H.D. Gilpin, 1837 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence from James Buchanan, 1837 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Business papers, account book, circa 1838 (Volume 90)
  - Business papers, correspondence, financial papers, 1838 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Business papers regarding estates and land, 1838-1839 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Business papers, Conynghan versus The Wilson and Company, Conyngham vs. Shaw, 1838 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence from H. D. Gilpin, James Buchanan, and Fr[ancis] P[ierce], 1838-1839 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence from family, 1838 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Business papers, correspondence (Charles Noble and Kensington Property), 1838-1844 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Business papers and correspondence, 1839 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence from family, 1839 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Business papers, correspondence, legal notes and papers, 1839-1840 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Business papers, correspondence, legal notes and papers, 1839-1840 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence from family, 1839-1840 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Business papers, collector's receipt book, 1839-1841 (Volume 91)
  - Correspondence, 1840-1844 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Business papers, correspondence, newspaper clippings, 1840-1845 (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence from family, 1840 (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Business papers, cash disbursements and receipt book, 1840-1841 (Volume 92)
  - Business papers, legal notes and papers, summons, 1841 (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Sarah Biddle Cabeen, papers and correspondence related to Library of Congress cataloging of her book "The Sister", 1841-1908 (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - Autobiography of Judge John M. Read, circa 1842 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Autobiography of Judge John M. Read, circa 1842 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Mortgage of Elisha Wilkinson to Doylestown Insurance Company of Bucks County, 1842 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Business papers, correspondence, newspaper clippings, 1842 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - "The Supreme Court of the United States", circa 1842 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence from family (mostly from Emily Read), 1842-1843 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Business papers, correspondence, legal papers, and notes, 1843 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Business papers, estate of Harriet McCall, estate of Pierre Antoine Blenon, 1843 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Business papers, correspondence, legal papers, and notes, 1843 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence from James Buchanan, Henry A. Muhlenberg, and H. D. Gilpin, 1844 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1844 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, legal notes, newspaper clippings, 1844 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Business papers and correspondence, 1845-1849 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1845-1849 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Bank books and check books, 1842, 1855-1868, 1873 (Box 38, Folder 1-8)
  - Correspondence from Joseph Pugh, Henry A. Muhlenberg, James Buchanan, and others, 1845 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence from Joseph Pugh, Henry A. Muhlenberg, John Cadwalader, George Plitt, and others, 1845 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence from Charles W. Caldwell, Joseph Pugh, George Meyfert, and Henry A. Muhlenberg, 1845 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence from family, 1846 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence regarding John M. Read's appointment to the Supreme Court, 1846 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Business papers, correspondence, estate papers, newspaper clippings, deeds, 1846 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Business papers, estate of Elisha Wilkinson, 1846-1847 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, business, 1846-1847 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Business papers, letterpress book, 1846-1852 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Business papers, 1846-1875 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, business papers, 1846-1886 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Documents relating to improvements of house and store on Chestnut Street, 1847 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Business papers, correspondence, estates, financial papers, 1847 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence from family, 1847 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence from John Meredith Read Jr., John Meredith Read, and others, 1848 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Business papers, master's notes of testimony: court of common pleas in equity, Charles Baeder, et al. vs. Tobias Bechler, 1848 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence from Samuel Davis, Mary McCall, and others, 1849 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence from Joseph Pugh, John Dickinson, Mary McCall, and others, 1850 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence from James Buchanan, 1851 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Business papers, Brief of the Counsel for the Appellee in the Supreme Court case for John Aspden vs. Matthias Aspden, 1851 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence from Michael Meyfert, Mary McCall and others, legal documents, newspaper clippings, report of sheriff's auction, 1851 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence from John Meredith Read Jr., Mary McCall, John Meredith Read, Michael Meyfert, William McCall, Samuel R. Meredith, and William Hyde, 1852 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Business papers, correspondence, newspaper clippings, 1853 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Business papers, William Weightman vs. Lewis P. Gebhard, 1853 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence from family (mostly William Hyde, John M. Read Jr.), 1853-1854 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence from family (mostly William Hyde, John M. Read Jr.), 1853-1854 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Business papers: Letterpress book, 1853 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, business, 1854 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence from family (mostly John M. Read Jr. and William Hyde), 1854 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence from family, 1854 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, business (mostly R. C. Grier and J. R. Thomson), 1854 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Business papers, correspondence (C. W. Housekeeper, J. R. Thomson, Magniac vs. Thomson), 1854 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, business, 1854 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, business, 1854 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Business papers, correspondence, estate papers, 1854 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Business papers, correspondence, estate papers (Samuel Davis, Robert Simpson, Michael Meyland), 1854 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Subject File: Act regarding Pennsylvania Railroad, 1854 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Business papers, estate of Harriet McCall, 1854 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Business papers, estate of Abraham Kernzie, 1854 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence from Samuel Davis, Charlotte Holbrooke, William H. Hyde, William Silver, John Meredith Read Jr. and others, 1855 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Business papers, letterpresses, 1855 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1855-1866 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Business papers, account book, 1855 January 23-1857 November 1 (Volume 93)
  - Correspondence from William H. Hyde, Marshall Woods, Charlotte M. Bridge, Charlotte M. Hollbrooke, Mary McCall, William McCall, John Meredith Read Jr. and others, 1856 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence from Victor Guillou, legal notes, promissory notes, 1857 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, business (Thaddeus Stevens and others regarding nomination), 1858 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Business papers, correspondence, legal notes, 1858 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Business papers, correspondence, legal notes, 1858 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Business papers, legal documents, 1858 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence from family, 1858 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Business papers, bills and receipts, 1858 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Business papers, bills and receipts, 1858 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence from John Meredith Jr., William H. Hyde, David Wilmot, Joseph A. Clay, Henry Wilson, and William Read, 1859 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence and other papers from Mary McCall, H. D. Maxwell, John H. Diehl, William H. Hyde, and others, 1859 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Business papers, correspondence, 1860-1865 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence to John M. Read Jr., 1860 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Business papers, correspondence, newspaper clippings, 1860 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Business papers, correspondence, bills and receipts, 1860 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Business papers, correspondence, memoranda, ephemera, 1860 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Business papers, correspondence, ephemera, newspaper clippings, legal documents, 1860 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence from family, 1860 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence from John M. Read Jr., 1860 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence from Senator Henry Wilson, 1860 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence from Charles H. T. Collis, 1860 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence from family, 1860 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, legal and business, 1861 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, legal and business, 1861 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence from George Harding, William H. Hyde, Emma H. Hyde, A. H. Thomson, and other family members, 1861 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence from Hannibal Hamlin, Henry Wilson, Salmon P. Chase, George Curtis, and others, 1861 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence from Charles H. T. Collis, Septima Sevy Collis, and Amelia Thompson, 1861 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence from John Meredith Jr. and Delphine Marie Pumpelly, 1861 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence from Edwin M. Stanton, Gideon Welles, Charles Sumner and others, 1862 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence from Charles H. T. Collis and Septima Sevy Collis, 1862 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence from John Meredith Read Jr., 1862 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Business papers, ephemera, newspaper clippings, 1862 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence from family, 1862 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence from Edward Gratz, J. C. Booth, and George Clymer, 1862 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence from family, 1862 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Business papers, correspondence, ephemera, memoranda, 1862 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Subject File: John Brown's will and souvenirs, 1862 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, business, 1863 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence from John Meredith Read Jr., 1863 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, business, 1863 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Business papers, correspondence, court cases, 1863 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Business papers, correspondence, pamphlets, copy of sketch of Fort Sumter, 1863 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence from family including Emma H. Hyde, William H. Hyde, and P. J. Horowitz, 1863 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence from Charles H. J. Collis and Septima Sevy Collis, 1863 (Box 50, Folder 6)